murex.com 2019-11-07

# PRIVACY POLICY | Murex

Last modified on 22/05/18

**What this policy covers**

Your privacy is important to us, and so is being transparent about how we collect, use, and share personal data and other information about you in compliance with the applicable regulations of the European Union and France regarding the processing of personal data, including in particular the Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of April 27, 2016 on the protection of personal data (the “General Data Protection Regulation” or “GDPR”).

This data privacy policy (“privacy policy”) is intended to help you understand:

WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

HOW WE USE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

HOW WE STORE AND SECURE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

HOW TO ACCESS AND CONTROL YOUR INFORMATION

OTHER IMPORTANT PRIVACY INFORMATION

This privacy policy covers the personal data we collect about you when you visit our website, download information or request for information, apply for a job or use our customer portals or our customer management relationship system. This Privacy Policy also explains your choices regarding the use of your information and the purposes of the processing we may make in respect of the data we collect about you. Your choices include how you can object to certain uses of information about you and how you can access and update certain information about you.

When we refer to "Murex," "we," or "us" in this Privacy Policy, we mean Murex S.A.S, which controls the information Murex collects when you use our services. We refer to all of our websites ([www.murex.com](http://www.murex.com/), [https://cz.murex.com](https://cz.murex.com/), _our[customer portals](https://murex.com/customerportal/loginOptions.html)_) as "Websites" in this policy. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, “Murex Services” refer to the access and use of the Websites, the management of all requests for information to Murex and more generally the services provided by Murex, as a software publisher, to its customer base.

WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

We collect certain personal data as defined in the GDPR of our candidates, business contacts (including the personnel of clients, prospects and partners) and other Websites users, as described below. 

**Information you provide to us**

We collect information about you when you input it into the Websites or otherwise provide it directly to us.

**Account and profile information:** We collect information about you, such as user names and passwords, when you register for an account, create or modify your profile, set preferences, sign-in through the Websites. We keep track of your preferences when you select settings within the Websites.

**Contact information:** We collect information such as your title, name, company, professional or personal email, phone and address when you access the community zone or the customer portal through the Websites, when you request additional information on Murex’s products or services, when you request our Services, when you apply for a job, when you register to an event organized or sponsored by Murex, or engage in communications with Murex in person, at an event or a business meeting.

**Content you provide through our Websites:** We collect content that you submit to our websites. For example, you provide content to us when you apply for a job and submit your curriculum vitae or when you participate in any interactive features, surveys or events.

**Information you provide through our communication channels for our Services:  **The Services also include access to our customer relationship management systems (“CRM”) and related tools and functionalities (such as JIRA), for instance when you request information on our products, our services or our developments, when you request our assistance or other services (including our maintenance services, our professional services or training services) or otherwise when you communicate with us in connection with the performance of our Services. You may choose to submit information about a support or project case. Whether you designate yourself as a technical contact, open a support ticket, register for a training, speak to one of our representatives directly or otherwise engage with our support and project teams, you will be asked to provide contact information (including possibly the contact information of end-users whom we need to liaise with to address your request), a summary of the case, and any other documentation, screenshots or other relevant information that would be helpful in resolving the case in accordance with the procedures applicable to our Services.

**Information for billing:** When you are designated as a billing representative by your employer, we collect information including your name and professional contact information.

**Customer relationship information:** Like all large companies, Murex uses a customer relationship database technology to manage and track our marketing and commercial performance. The bulk of the personal data we collect relates to individual employees of our clients and other companies with which we have an existing business relationship. In addition to contact information, we collect your responses to targeted marketing campaign, participation to events and other business information included by Murex professionals based on their personal interactions with you.

**Information we collect automatically when you use the Websites.**

We collect information about you when you use, browse and take certain actions on our Websites.

**Your use of the Websites:** We keep track of certain information about you when you visit and interact with any of our Websites. This information includes the features you use; the pages viewed; the number and frequency; frequently used search terms; date and time of consultation.

**Connection information:** We collect information about standard information from your web browser (such as browser type and browser language) and your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address Services.

**Cookies and other tracking technologies:** Murex uses cookies to provide functionality and to recognize you on Websites. For more information, please see our Cookies and Tracking Notice, which includes information on how to control or opt out of these cookies and tracking technologies.

**Information we receive from other sources:  **We receive information from third party services you might be using. For example, we receive information about you when you apply for a job for Murex and you have provided your consent to the headhunter or recruitment agency or we receive information about your participation to an event we are sponsoring when you have provided your consent to the organizer. You should always check the privacy settings and notices in these third-party services to understand what data may be disclosed to us or shared with Murex. We may also receive your contact information when you express interests in Murex products and services in a third-party website or with a partner.

HOW WE USE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

How we use the information we collect depends in part on which Services you use, how you use them, and any preferences you have communicated to us.

We collect and process information about you only where such processing is lawful under the GDPR and other applicable EU and national laws. The legal basis for the processing of your data depends on the Services you use and how you use them. This means that we collect and process your information only where:

  * You give us consent to do so for a specific purpose;
  * The processing satisfies a legitimate interest as defined in the GDPR (which is not overridden by your data protection rights or interests) to improve our Services, to market and promote our products and Services, or to protect our legal rights and interests; 
  * We need to process your data to comply with a legal obligation; or
  * The processing of your data is necessary to enable us to take certain necessary steps at your request prior to entering into a contract or for the performance of a contract with you.

Below are the specific purposes for which we use the information we collect about you, either with your consent or based on the legitimate interest described above, as applicable:

**To provide the Services and personalize your experience on the Websites:** We use information about you to provide the Services to you, including, authenticate you when you log in, provide customer support, and access to information dedicated to our clients and partners.

**To improve our Services:** We are always looking for ways to make our Services smarter, faster, secure, integrated and useful to you. We use collective learnings about how people interact with our websites, to identify trends, usage, activity patterns and areas for integration and improvement of the Websites. We also test and analyze certain new features with some users before rolling the feature out to all users.

**To communicate with you about the Services:** We use your contact information to send communications via email and within the Services, including responding to your comments, questions and requests for information, and sending you technical notices, updates, and administrative messages. If you object to the processing of your personal data, we might not be able to fulfil your requests or to inform you about changes regarding the Services.

**To market, promote, and drive engagement with the Services:** We use your contact information to send communications that may be of specific interest to you as an employee of a company with whom we have or look to develop a business relationship, including by email. These communications are aimed at driving engagement and maximizing the value of our Services for our clients, prospects and business partners, including information about new features, survey requests, news, and events we think may be of interest. We communicate with you about new product offers. We also communicate with you to manage your registration to corporate, online or industry event that Murex organizes or sponsors.

**To process job applications:** We use your contact information and additional information you provided us for recruitment-related processes. We always request for your consent to process this information as part of the job application process. If you do not consent, we will not be able to process your application.

**Customer services:** We use your information to resolve issues you encounter, to respond to your requests for assistance, to analyze log files, to enhance your user experience and to improve the Services.

**To protect our legitimate business interests and legal rights:** Where required by law or where we believe it is necessary to protect our legal rights, interests and the interests of others, we use information about you in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory, and audit functions.

We are not in the business of selling information about you and we will not sell your information with advertisers or other third parties for commercial purposes.

We share information we collect with our personnel, with our affiliated companies and, in some cases, with certain subcontractors, to the extent necessary for the fulfillment of the Services.

**Relevance:** Only the relevant personnel of Murex or its affiliates who needs to be given access to the information for the purposes mentioned above will be given access to your information. For instance, only the members of the Human Resources department and other relevant departments of Murex involved in a recruitment process may access the personal data you decide to supply on the Websites when submitting a job application to Murex.

**Service providers:** From time to time, in order to provide you with our Services, we may work with subcontractors who provide website and application development, hosting, maintenance, backup, storage, infrastructure, and analysis or other services for us, which may require them to access or use information about you. If a service provider needs to access information about you to perform services on our behalf, they do so under instruction from us, including abiding by policies and procedures designed to protect your information and a strict confidentiality obligation.

**International transfers of information we collect:** The information that we collect is stored in France. For the purpose of the Services, we may share your information with affiliates located outside the European Union, including in countries that may not have equivalent privacy and data protection laws to E.U. regulations on data protection. In this case, we process your information in accordance with standard contractual clauses on data protection, whose terms have been approved by the European Commission, to safeguard the transfer of information we collect from the European Economic Area and Switzerland. We can provide further information upon request (see 'Contact us' below).

**Links to Third-Party sites:** The Services may include links that direct you to other websites or services whose privacy practices may differ from ours. Your use of and any information you submit to any of those third-party sites is governed by their privacy policies, not this one. You should review carefully the privacy policy of such third parties.

**Compliance with enforcement requests and applicable laws; enforcement of our rights:** In exceptional circumstances, we may share information about you with a third party if we believe that sharing is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request (b) enforce our agreements, policies and terms of service, (c) protect the security or integrity of our products and services, (d) protect Murex, our customers or the public from harm or illegal activities.

HOW WE STORE AND SECURE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

Murex is committed to the protection of the personal data that you have provided us with in order to preserve their confidentiality and prevent any unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of your personal data.

**Information storage and security**

The personnel of Murex and its affiliates who is given access to your personal data for the purposes set out above in this privacy policy is bound by a strict confidentiality obligation, whose breach can be sanctioned by disciplinary action and/or other sanctions in accordance with applicable labor laws.

As part of the information security policy implemented by Murex for the protection of its own sensitive information and its clients’ information, Murex applies organizational and technical measures to ensure appropriate security of the personal data we collect, including protection against unauthorized or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage, and to ensure that such personal data can only be accessed by the authorized personnel of Murex or its affiliates, and only for the purposes described in this privacy policy.

Though Murex considers that it applies sophisticated measures, in particular, for the protection of the information system environment on which the data we collect are stored, it remains that no transfer of data via the Internet can be fully protected from unlawful access by third parties. Communications via the Internet may potentially be intercepted, lost or modified and such risks remain beyond Murex’s reasonable control.

Accordingly, you acknowledge and accept that Murex may not be held liable, for any reason whatsoever, for any damage of whatever nature resulting from the transmission of personal data, and that all communication to the Websites is at your own risk.

HOW LONG WE KEEP INFORMATION

How long we keep information we collect about you depends on the type of information, as described in further detail below. After such time, we will either delete or anonymize your information or, if this is not possible (for example, because the information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your information from any further use until deletion is possible.

**Account information:** We retain your account information until you delete your account. We also retain some of your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, to enforce our agreements, to support business operations and to continue to develop and improve our Services.

**Information you share on the Services:** If your account is deactivated or disabled, some of your information and the content you have provided will remain to allow your team members or other users in your organization to make full use of the Services. For example, if a support case is still not resolved, the information submitted in the case will remain.

**Marketing information:** If you have elected to receive marketing emails from us, we retain information about your marketing preferences unless you specifically ask us to delete such information. We retain information derived from cookies and other tracking technologies for a maximum of twelve (12) months from the date such information was created. We delete inactive contacts in our marketing and CRM databases after three (3) years.

**Job application information:** In the case of recruitment process, we store the information you shared with us up to two (2) years.

HOW TO ACCESS AND CONTROL YOUR INFORMATION

You have certain choices available to you when it comes to your information. Below is a summary of those choices, how to exercise them and any limitations. We will respond to requests about this within a reasonable timeframe. 

**Control of your information and withdrawal of your consent**

Here are the choices you have to control your information or where you want to withdraw your consent to the processing of your information:

**Opt-out of communications:** You may opt out of receiving communications from us about news, events and product and services by using the unsubscribe link within each email, updating your preferences within our preference center, or by contacting us as provided below to have your contact information removed from our email list. Even after you opt out from receiving these messages from us, you will continue to receive operational messages from us regarding our Services.

**Turn off Cookie controls:** Relevant browser-based cookie controls are described in our Cookies and Tracking Notice at the end of this privacy policy.

**Send "Do Not Track" signals:** Some browsers have incorporated "Do Not Track" (DNT) features that can send a signal to the websites you visit indicating you do not wish to be tracked. Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret the DNT signal, our Services do not currently respond to browser DNT signals.

**Your other rights regarding your data**

You have the right to request a copy of your information, to object to our use of your information (including for marketing purposes), to request the deletion or correction of your information or otherwise to request that our processing of your information be restricted. Please note that we may not be able to provide the Services to you if we cannot access or use your information.

We remind you that you also have the right to lodge a complaint with the CNIL ([www.cnil.fr](http://www.cnil.fr/)), which is the competent supervisory authority in France in respect of data privacy, if you consider that Murex has acted in violation of applicable laws and regulations on data privacy in respect of your personal data that you have submitted through the Services and that Murex has failed to address your request regarding your personal data.

You may contact us as provided in the Contact Us section below to request assistance.

OTHER IMPORTANT PRIVACY INFORMATION

**Our policy towards children**

The Services are not directed to individuals under 16. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. If we become aware that a child under 16 has provided us with personal information, we will take steps to delete such information. If you become aware that a child has provided us with personal information, please ask his parents / legal guardians to request for deletion by contacting our Marketing department in the 'Contact us' details.

**Changes to our privacy policy**

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. We encourage you to review our privacy policy whenever you use the Services to stay informed about our data privacy practices.

**Contact Us**

**For job application:** If you are a job applicant who has submitted contact information to Murex, please contact the Human Resources Department of Murex for all requests regarding your job application or otherwise to exercise your right to request access to, rectification or erasure of your personal data. 

Email: [mxrh@murex.com](mailto:mxrh@murex.com),

or otherwise by mail at the following address: Murex SAS, Human Resources Department 8 rue Bellini 75116 Paris  

**For other purposes:** for all requests, other than those related to a job application, or otherwise to exercise your right to request access to, rectification or erasure of your personal data, or to object to, or request a restriction to, the processing of your data, please contact the Marketing Department of Murex

by email, at the following address: [mkg@murex.com](mailto:mkg@murex.com),

or otherwise by mail at the following address: Murex SAS, Marketing Department 8 rue Bellini 75116 Paris

We will use reasonable efforts to respond to your request within a reasonable period of time, depending on the nature and context of your request.

Where you make the request by email, and unless otherwise specified in your request, the information that you are requesting will be provided to you by email. 

**To contact our DPO officer:** If you have questions or complaints regarding Murex’s privacy policy, or more generally our practices regarding data protection, or if you have a reason to believe that Murex has failed to respond to your requests regarding your personal data or that the personal data you provided on the Websites has been misused or compromised, you can contact Murex’s Data Protection Officer by email at the following address: [MurexDPO@murex.com](mailto:MurexDPO@murex.com).

COOKIES & TRACKING NOTICE

HOW TO BLOCK OR DELETE COOKIES

You can block ‘cookies’ either by deleting the ‘cookies’ stored on your computer or by configuring your computer to this end. Please note that some of the Website’s functions will no longer be available once ‘cookies’ are disabled.

**For Mozilla Firefox:  **

Select the 'Tools' menu, then 'Options' 

Click on the 'Privacy' icon

Find the ‘Cookies’ menu and select the required options

**For Microsoft Internet Explorer 6.0:**

Select the 'Tools' menu, then 'Internet Options' 

Click on the 'Privacy' icon 

Select the level desired using the cursor

**For Microsoft Internet Explorer 7 and above:**

Select the 'Tools' menu, then 'Internet Options' • Click on the ‘Security’ icon

Select 'Internet' then 'Customize Level'

Find the ‘Cookies’ menu and select the required options

**For Netscape 6.X and 7.X:  **

Select the 'Edit' menu, then 'Preferences'

Click on 'Privacy' then 'Security' 

Find the ‘Cookies’ menu and select the required options

**For Opera 6.0 and above:**

Select the 'File' menu, then 'Preferences'

Select 'Privacy'

Find the ‘Cookies’ menu and select the required options

**For Safari**

Select the ‘Edit’ menu in the menu bar

Select ‘Preferences’ in the drop down menu

Select the ‘Security’ icon

Ensure that in the ‘Allow Cookies’ section the option ‘Always or Only From Visited Websites’ is ticked to allow ‘cookies’

To block ‘cookies’, select the ‘Never’ option. It is not possible to block ‘cookies’ on a case-by-case basis with this browser.

**For Chrome**

Click on the 'Chrome' icon in the toolbar

Select ‘Settings’.

At the bottom of the page, click on ‘Show advanced settings’.

In the 'Privacy' section, click on ‘Content settings’.

To enable and disable ‘cookies’, proceed as follows:

To enable ‘cookies’, select ‘Allow local data to be set (recommended)’.

To disable ‘cookies’, select ‘Block sites from setting any data’.

Click on ‘OK’ to save.
